Imperial Diary.
Year 10,191. Third comment.
The battle for Arrakis
took everyone by surprise.
There were no witnesses.
The Harkonnen operation
was perpetrated overnight,
without warning or
declaration of war.
By morning, the
Atreides were no more.
All died in the dark.
And the Emperor said...
nothing.
Since that night, my father
has not been the same.
Nor have I.
His inaction is difficult
for me to accept.
For, I know he loved Duke
Leto Atreides like a son.
But my father's
always been guided
by the calculus of power.
This would not be the first time the
Harkonnens have done his dirty work.
In the shadows of
Arrakis lie many secrets...
but the darkest of
them all may remain.
The end of House Atreides.
Sister, Father is dead.
Shouldn't you go
back to the stars,
be with him?
I'm afraid I won't have enough
time to fix things before your coming.
This world is beyond cruelty.
Stay here.
Never stand with your
back towards the open.
How many times do I
have to tell you that?
You okay?
- Yeah.
- How 'bout her?
She's fine.
They do not
usually venture this deep.
They wanna make sure
no Atreides escaped.
You
think too much of yourself.
No, no, we are
in the deep desert.
Only Fremen can survive here.
They were here
for us, not for you.
Don't worry.
I'm taking you somewhere
they will never find us.
Filthy water.
It's full of chemicals, but good
enough for cooling systems.
Don't let it out.
You okay?
Don't let that out.
Don't let it out!
- I'm okay.
- Are you sure?
You fought well...
once you woke up.
I wasn't sleeping.
No, no, no. I'll do it.
Lor... Lord Rabban.
Now that the spice
fields have been secured,
I strongly recommend bringing
all troops out of Fremen territories.
We're losing too
many men to the desert.
Rats.
- I beg your pardon?
- We're losing men to rats.
Fremen! I can't
confirm, my Lord.
Communications are
hectic in the open sands.
Your orders were to
control the whole planet.
- We are.
- I see only half of it.
As you may recall,
the South is
uninhabitable, my Lord.
May I suggest you get some rest?
Rats! Hairy rats!
Kill them! Kill
them! Kill them all!
Kill them all!
Rats!
He's asking why we're so late.
He thinks you're spies.
He
said... - I got that.
- Thanks.
- Stay close to me.
Sietch Tabr.
Lisan al-Gaib!
Look how your Bene Gesserit
propaganda has taken root.
Some of them already
think I'm their messiah.
Others...
false prophet.
I must sway the non-believers.
If they follow me, we can
disrupt spice production.
That's the only way I
can get to the Emperor.
Your father didn't
believe in revenge.
Yeah, well, I do.
What is happening?
What is it?
There is
spice in the food.
Woman.
Come with me.
Thirty-eight
million decaliters.
None of us, even dying of
thirst, would ever drink this water.
This is...
sacred.
Jamis' water.
We have a thousand such places.
When we have enough water,
the Lisan al-Gaib will
change the face of Arrakis.
He will bring back the
trees. He will bring back...
a Green Paradise.
So many souls.
Never give your water away,
not even for the dead.
Why are you showing me this?
Because you are Bene Gesserit.
Because you understand
the prophecies.
The mother of the Lisan al-Gaib
will be a Reverend Mother.
Our Reverend Mother is dying.
You want
me to take her place?
Yes, I do.
You believe in Paul?
There are signs.
Yes.
What if I would refuse?
Then, he's
not Lisan al-Gaib,
and you have no
purpose to serve.
What else is left to do then but
to return your water to the well?
It's an honor, isn't it?
I think you should feel honored.
Well, it was a choice
between this or death,
so, you know, forgive
me if I'm not flattered.
How does one become
a Reverend Mother?
It's different from
one culture to another.
Here on Arrakis, I have no idea.
You're afraid.
Reverend Mothers are tasked
with holding the memories
of all the Reverend Mothers
that came before them,
so I'll be given centuries
of pain and sorrow.
Is it dangerous?
It's lethal for men.
That's for sure.
What are you guys
laughing about?
Don't bother.
You don't believe in all this?
No, we don't.
These are
old Southern beliefs.
Southern beliefs?
Southern tribes believe a messiah
will come to deliver us from evil.
You don't believe
in the Lisan al-Gaib?
We believe in Fremen.
You want to control people,
you tell them a messiah will come.
Then they'll wait for centuries.
Now, we must pray.
What about him?
Stilgar?
He's from the South. You
didn't notice his accent?
What'll happen to my mother?
I must not
fear. Fear is the mind-killer.
Fear, the little death that
brings total obliteration.
I will face my fear. I will...
What is it?
Drink!
She's right. She's right!
It's no miracle.
My mother was
trained to do that.
Poison transmutation is something
advanced Bene Gesserit can do.
I'm not the Mahdi.
I'm not here to lead.
Let me fight beside
you. That's all I'm asking.
How are you?
Better.
How is she?
She was
frightened, but she's...
she's okay.
Paul.
She talks to me.
She believes in you.
She says...
You're so close now.
Only one step remains and you
will become the Kwisatz Haderach.
Only one step remains.
You must do what I did.
You must drink
the Water of Life.
And your mind, it's gon... it's
gonna open and you will see.
If you wanna fight
with us, first thing, you must learn
to be one with the desert.
So, here is a tent
and enough food.
I want you to cross that
small erg and come back.
Travel by night.
You know how to
use a paracompass?
Yes.
Anything else I should know?
Beside the worms
and the Harkonnens,
beware of the trapdoor spiders.
Centipedes are very
nasty. Not the big ones.
They are harmless.
But the little ones, you have
to worry about. And...
Don't ever, ever
listen to the jinn.
- The jinn?
- Jinn.
Desert spirits.
They whisper at night.
They, they can possess you.
Really, be careful.
They are demons.
But it's true. Don't
listen to them.
Jamis.
You sandwalk
like a drunk lizard.
Yeah, I'm doing
pretty good so far.
Yeah, well, you're not
even in worm territory yet.
You have to
break up your rhythm.
Like this.
Now, that's interesting
because in the filmbooks I've studied,
the anthropologists say, in order to
properly sandwalk, you actually have...
Never mind. Please keep going.
You know, I'm the only one who believes
you're gonna make it until summer?
Everyone else thinks you
won't make it two weeks.
If you wanna follow
us in the desert,
you need to know
how windtraps work.
So, listen to me.
They're simple, but they
require constant attention.
This right here, it
captures the moisture
and then it carries
it into that pocket.
And these are the filters.
They need to be
changed every three days.
What?
Stop looking at me like that.
He's training
with the Fremen.
He will be back
soon. Don't worry.
You're right. If we want
to protect your brother,
we need all the Fremen
to believe in the prophecy.
We must convert the
non-believers one by one.
We need to start
with the weaker ones.
The vulnerable ones.
The ones who fear us.
Hey, get out of here. Go.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Let's go! Move!
Load.
Chani!
Reload!
Reload.
Watch out!
Its shield will
only open when it fires.
I know that. What
do you think I'm trying to do?
I'll trigger it. On
my signal. Be ready.
Go!
Shit!
Go! Go!
Who taught you
to fight like that?
My old masters.
They were close friends.
They were massacred.
Alongside my father.
You've been fighting the
Harkonnens for decades.
My family's been
fighting them for centuries.
I know everything about them.
Their habits, their ways of thinking.
You know everything
about the desert.
You harness the
very power of it.
We can stop them together, bury
them in the sand where they belong.
So that this planet can
be yours once more.
What
would you have us do?
What would you do, Stilgar?
I? I would... would
strike even further north.
Then I will go further north.
And the further north you
go, the more likely it is you die.
I see strength in you.
Come, come.
You shall be know
among us as Usul.
- Usul.
Usul. And now,
a Fedaykin is a fighter
and needs a war name.
You must choose.
How do you call the...
The small desert mouse, again?
- Muad'Dib?
- Muad'Dib.
No, no, no.
Muad'Dib is wise in
the ways of the desert.
Muad'Dib...
creates his own water.
The constellation that points to
the North Star, we call Muad'Dib.
"The One Who Points the Way."
That is a powerful name.
Now you are our brother.
Paul Muad'Dib Usul.
Muad'Dib Usul.
Muad'Dib Usul..
Muad'Dib.
Usul.
Hey! Stilgar!
Father, I found my way.
It's breathtaking.
Look. Right there. Spice.
Arrakis is so beautiful
when the sun is low.
Where you're from, does
water really fall from the sky?
Yes.
Sometimes it rains
for weeks on Caladan.
Where you see sand
here, imagine water.
Our castle stands on
cliffs high above the sea.
If you dive in, you
can't reach the bottom.
- You dive in?
- Yes, it's called swimming.
I don't... I
don't believe you, Usul.
Usul.
What's your secret name?
Sihaya.
What does that mean?
Means Desert Spring.
"Desert Spring."
- I love it.
- I hate it.
It's from some stupid prophecy.
I prefer Chani.
I prefer Chani, too, then.
Do you think Stilgar
would teach me?
- To ride?
- Yeah.
No.
Only Fremen ride worms.
Well, I thought I'd
become one, didn't I?
By name, not by blood.
Your blood comes from
Dukes and Great Houses.
We don't have that here.
Here, we're equal,
men and women alike.
What we do, we do
for the benefit of all.
Well, I'd very much
like to be equal to you.
Paul Muad'Dib Usul...
maybe you could be Fremen.
Maybe I'll show you the way.
Rabban.
Fremen
attacks on your watch.
Your orders were to restore
spice production to full capacity.
Do you know what
it means if you fail?
The Emperor will take
spice out of our control.
Tighten your grip, Rabban.
Uncle.
Or
feel mine on your neck.
Usul? Usul.
It's okay. It's okay.
Hey.
I'm here, I'm here.
It's been a while since you've
had one of those nightmares.
Tell me,
what was it about?
Nothing's clear.
It's only fragments.
I'm in the South, and
I'm following someone.
And it triggers a holy war.
Millions and millions of
people starving to death...
because of me.
You've been exposed
to spice for a long time.
It can create weird dreams.
It's a big day.
We can ask
Stilgar to call it off.
No. I'm fine.
Usul.
I tuned it myself.
- Here.
- Thanks.
Don't try to impress anyone.
You are brave. We all know that.
Heh? Be simple.
Be direct. Nothing fancy.
- Nothing fancy.
- Hey, I'm serious.
Nothing fancy or you
will shame my teaching.
I won't shame you. I understand.
Shai-Hulud decides today if
you become Fremen, or if you die.
Hey, Muad'Dib!
Lower.
Okay. Okay.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
Okay.
Okay. Okay!
Come on!
Whoa!
You're a rider!
I know they do.
Our task in the
North is nearly done.
They believe in Paul.
Now we go South.
There are millions of
fundamentalists there.
They will protect
him when he comes.
The Kwisatz Haderach
will be born in the South.
As long as I breathe.
What's wrong?
Chani.
There will be trouble.
What are you talking about?
Chani, what do you mean?
The way they look at you.
They worship you now.
The Fedaykin, they
count your victories.
They say you can see the future.
Whisper, " Lisan al-Gaib."
I'm no messiah.
I'm a Fedaykin of Sietch Tabr.
Yet, we have a Bene
Gesserit among us,
fanning the flames
of your legend,
saying you're the One.
She says you should
be coming with us.
You know I can't.
She's asking why.
Because I must continue
fighting in the North,
to protect you down
there in the South.
She says she can
tell when you lie.
Tell her that's because our mother
keeps spreading dangerous tales.
What is she saying now?
She says you're blinded by love,
and she reminds you that
you must reserve your hand
for the most strategic alliance.
She's also wondering why
you don't believe in who you are.
I do believe.
I believe I matter
to these people.
And I believe I'm making
a difference in this war.
We're nearly at
the gates of the city.
- That's not what she means.
- I know what she means.
Do you not think I also feel
the weight of the prophecy?
It's not a prophecy.
It's a story that
you keep telling,
but it's not their
story, it's yours.
They deserve to be
led by one of their own.
What your people did to
this world is heartbreaking.
We gave them
something to hope for.
That's not hope!
I'll be waiting for you.
All of us.
Those storms look bad.
- How much?
- We lost...
eighty percent of our last crop.
My Lord Rabban, you should
not leave the security perimeter.
Security perimeter? The
rats are already inside.
The Fremen Demon
might be with them.
I hope so.
We're
tracking them, my Lord.
Today, Muad'Dib dies!
Where is he?
Still negative, my Lord.
Why do I have
to do everything myself?
Open range!
Range open.
Life. Delta, delta, delta.
I've lost them.
- Strike!
- Yes, my Lord.
Muad'Dib!
Show yourself!
Muad'Dib! Muad'Dib! Muad'Dib!
For Muad'Dib!
Muad'Dib.
Some new Fremen prophet?
It's not the first time
we've had frictions with the Fremen.
None of this magnitude.
So, my dear daughter...
how would you deal
with this prophet?
If this Muad'Dib
is a religious figure,
you can't use direct force.
Repression only
makes a religion flourish.
You'll only end up
humiliating yourself.
You underestimate my Sardaukar.
You underestimate
the power of faith.
Her Highness proves once again
that she was my most acute student.
- You'd send assassins?
- No.
Prophets get
stronger when they die.
Let the conflict on
Arrakis turn into war.
You then bring
peace. As a savior.
You'd be a formidable empress.
Muad'Dib. The prophet.
The one who points the way.
These are our own
religious patterns, aren't they?
This is our doing.
Muad'Dib means kangaroo mouse.
An unusual war
name for a Fremen.
- What if Paul Atreides were still alive?
- Enough!
This must not come out. Even
to your father's ears. Understand?
I do, Reverend Mother.
If Paul
is alive, he likely knows the truth.
And should the
Great Houses learn
that your father was behind
the liquidation of the Atreides,
your father will face
war and lose the throne.
Then what hope is there?
Hope?
We are Bene Gesserit.
We don't hope, we plan.
Paul is not our only prospect.
The Baron's youngest nephew, Feyd-Rautha
Harkonnen, will inherit Arrakis.
He may be the answer.
Feyd-Rautha? He's psychotic.
That's irrelevant.
The question is,
can we control him?
And I intend to find out.
Would you like
some fresh meat, my darlings?
Lungs? Or liver?
What would
you like? I hear they're big today.
Your new blades for
this very special day,
na-Baron, Feyd-Rautha.
A notch off balance.
It's the tip.
Should be sharper.
Come.
I won't
die like a fool.
Kill me now.
No drug for you today, Atreides.
Welcome to Giedi Prime, sisters.
I hope your travels
were agreeable.
A long way
to come just to watch our prospect
risk his life, Lady Fenring.
No fear.
These fights are all for show.
But we'll get a
good look at him.
Feyd-Rautha! Feyd-Rautha!
That slave isn't drugged.
That bug is walking straight.
You should cancel the fight.
Don't spoil my
nephew's birthday.
Happy birthday, dear nephew.
Why do they not stop the fight?
Plans within plans.
Show me who you are.
There he is.
Back! Back!
Stay back!
You have
fought well, Atreides.
Feyd-Rautha! Feyd-Rautha!
He's impressive, indeed.
The
slave wasn't drugged.
You tried to kill me.
This morning you were a playboy,
feared and envied,
but tonight you're a hero.
My gift to you.
I ought to drown
you in that tub.
Don't be hasty.
I have another gift for you.
A bigger one.
Arrakis.
What about Rabban?
He has
failed to protect spice production.
Rabban will be reassigned.
Tame Arrakis, Feyd.
Free the spice. I'll
make you Emperor.
Emperor?
How?
The Emperor helped
me destroy the Atreides.
He lent his own
army to the cause.
A serious crime.
If it came to light, the Great
Houses would rise against him.
And then...
who will sit on the throne?
Feyd-Rautha Harkonnen.
You're following me.
Am I?
I may have gotten lost.
Will you show me the way out
of this maze, my Lord na-Baron?
We've met, haven't we?
I don't think so.
I'm Lady Margot Fenring.
I'm here to honor
your coming of age.
You're not allowed
in this section.
How did you get past the guards?
The guards?
May I ask,
what are you doing here?
You're not taking part
in your own celebrations?
You're Bene Gesserit.
And
what makes you say that?
I remember now.
I dreamed about you last night.
A pleasant dream, I hope.
Don't
mock me, woman.
I wouldn't dare.
I know your Bene
Gesserit tricks.
And what do you know
about the Bene Gesserit?
Tell me.
Something wrong?
I don't
recognize this place.
This is the guest wing.
Where are you going?
To my room.
Come. To. Me.
Kneel.
Put your right hand in the box.
A
sociopath. Of high intelligence.
Driven. Cruel.
But strongly motivated by honor.
He yearns to be hurt.
He loves pain.
Can he be redeemed?
He can be controlled.
He's sexually vulnerable.
And?
The bloodline is secured.
Female, as you requested.
You did well, Margot.
Respectfully, why didn't
you test him yourself?
I'm a motherly figure.
And based on what happened
between him and his own mother,
I didn't expect to be effective.
What happened between
him and his mother?
He murdered her.
Desire and humiliation.
Those are his levers.
If Feyd-Rautha
prevails on Arrakis,
we shall know
how to control him.
Rid me of this Fremen Demon.
Feyd-Rautha! Feyd-Rautha!
Feyd-Rautha!
♪ Do away with these idiots ♪
♪ I blame ♪
♪ My stillsuit Is full of piss ♪
♪ My hand is caked in sand ♪
♪ Save me from
These utter morons ♪
♪ Another world, another land ♪
We're in.
Juicy?
Juicy, juicy.
Well, it
was nice knowing ya.
Yeah?
Radar's clear. We're clear.
Cooking time.
Juicy, juicy.
Yeah, I got a meter reading...
All
right, guys, worms are on their way.
- Watch out for abrasions.
- Get ready to dock.
It's gonna get hot.
Crank 'em
up! Throw them up!
Hold!
Mine! Mine!
Get moving!
- East! East!
- Get clear!
Let's get out of here!
Incoming!
Don't run, fight!
We're in
deep Fremen shit.
Holy Mother.
Fuck.
I recognized
your footsteps...
- old man.
- No.
You young pup.
You young pup!
After
the Battle of Arrakeen,
I was able to negotiate a trip
back home for the survivors.
Thanks to these guys.
Why'd you stay?
Well, I wanted blood.
Rabban's head?
Well, since Muad'Dib's
been driving Rabban crazy,
the smuggling business
has been quite profitable.
Gurney Halleck the smuggler.
Paul Muad'Dib.
I've heard many
stories about Muad'Dib.
None of them pretty.
You see the fear?
When our
resources are limited...
fear is all we have.
How many men with you?
- Two hundred.
- Two hundred?
Do you realize what you're
able to achieve with 200 men?
Incredible fighters.
Duncan said there
were millions of them.
In the Deep South, yes.
Well, what are you waiting for?
With thousands of these guys, you
could take control of the entire planet.
It's your father's dream.
What are you afraid of?
Hey!
Worship, Gurney.
They used to be friends.
Now they're followers.
Muad'Dib, the Prophet.
Why is that a bad thing? Use it.
It's not that simple.
You have the power to avenge
your father, and you're afraid to use it?
Spice opened my mind, Gurney.
I can foresee things.
If I go South, all my
visions lead to horror.
Billions of corpses
scattered across the galaxy.
All dying because of me.
Because you lose control.
Because I gain it.
That's a lot of water.
Chani.
What? Look
at him, he's hopeless.
He's family.
Really?
No need to be a prophet
to see what's ahead.
Your path leads to war.
You know that.
So, war is coming.
What will you do when you
feel its breath upon your neck?
If you don't want to raise
an army in the South,
you may still have an option.
Fire power...
which you don't have.
And here I am.
I know where your father
hid the family atomics.
Every House
possesses an atomic arsenal.
I thought ours had been lost.
It's huge, Chani. It
could change everything.
I could aim the bombs
at the main spice fields.
He who can destroy a
thing has the real control of it.
So, you can
control it and not us?
You promised me
you didn't want power.
No matter what I do,
you still don't trust me.
'Cause you're a
foreigner. Like your friend.
I'm not a foreigner.
Not to me.
But to the desert, you are.
My allegiance is to you.
To the Fremen.
I'm doing this for all of us.
Do you believe me?
I'll talk to Stilgar.
There.
It's right under
everybody's noses.
Not clever.
That's the idea.
Nobody would ever look in
there because it's obvious.
Not clever.
Did you find it?
I didn't look for it.
How many heads exactly?
Enough to blow
up the whole planet.
It's a figure of speech.
You know what I mean.
Only with
your genetic heritage.
Your
great-great-grandfather's legacy.
The 92 original Atreides
family's atomic warheads.
Now that, that is power.
Imperial
Diary. Year 10,191.
Eighth comment.
Reports from the south
of Arrakis arrive rarely.
These are barren, burnt
lands hidden by sandstorms
which stretch a thousand
miles across the equator.
Nothing can live
there without faith.
Which is why our Bene Gesserit
missionaries have been so productive there.
Through them, we are receiving
reports of a mysterious figure
taking grip on the imaginations
of the Southern
fundamentalist tribes.
A new Reverend
Mother from the North...
spreading word of the imminent
arrival of the Lisan al-Gaib,
"The Voice from
the Outer World."
With religious fervor
rising in the South,
and Muad'Dib strangling
spice production in the North,
everything points to
the escalation of war.
Quiet.
Listen carefully.
Soon a man is going
to visit your temple
and he may want you
to perform the rites.
Reverend Mother,
it is forbidden.
Let him try!
What the hell?
Chani!
Chani.
Sietch Tabr.
Old fashioned artillery.
Genius.
We're literally melting
rock on their heads.
I want to go on the
ground. Prepare my troops.
My Lord. I would recommend you
stay inside. There was...
Bring his body to my quarters.
My poor darlings are hungry.
There was no food
for them on the flight.
What
are you doing here?
It's early morning. What
Kiss my feet, brother.
I'm gonna eviscerate your...
You
humiliated our family.
You humiliated me.
Kiss...
or die.
We're even now.
Embarrass
our family one more time...
it will be the last.
They didn't even
engage on the ground,
like honorable fighters.
Usul, in the South...
only leaders are
allowed to speak.
- You must take my place.
- I can't do that.
It is a good time to
cross blades with me.
I am weak. I am an
easy kill, Muad'Dib.
I'd rather cut off my own hand.
We need you. We need the
Lisan al-Gaib to lead our people.
You know what I
think of all that, Stilgar.
I don't care what
you believe. I believe.
I didn't see it coming.
The Harkonnens aren't done here.
They just went back to reload.
We're setting thumpers.
We're moving
everyone to the South.
I'll stay behind and
cover your retreat.
- What are you talking about?
- Chani, I can't go with you.
You know why.
- I'll stay, too.
- Nobody stays but me.
- Paul.
- That's an order, Gurney Halleck! Go South!
Protect my mother.
- My Lord.
- Muad'Dib.
He's afraid of the
fundamentalists.
And he should be.
Don't resist.
Talk to me, Jamis.
You
see only fragments.
You cannot see the future
without seeing the past.
To unlock your mind, you
need to drink the Water of Life...
and you will see everything.
A good hunter always
climbs the highest dune before his hunt.
He needs to see...
as far as he can see.
You need to see.
You must
drink the Water of Life.
Your mind, it's gonna open,
and you will see.
The world has
made choices for us.
If I go South, I might lose you.
You will never lose me,
Paul Atreides.
Not as long as you
stay who you are.
I'll cross the storms with you.
Go South.
Bring your people to safety.
And then I will do
what must be done.
Where?
Spy. Left behind.
No trace of the others.
They've gone
South to hide in the storms.
Send this message to the Baron.
The North is
liberated and secured.
Harvest spice at will.
Yes, na-Baron.
You killed nine of my
men with one single blade.
She won't talk.
Tell her that's fine.
I already know
everything I need to know.
Only pleasure remains.
Now
that you can see our past,
you can see your future.
Brother,
my dearest brother,
you are not prepared
for what is to come.
You'll now learn the
truth about our family.
And it will hurt
you to the core.
Paul...
Don't worry. I'm with you.
I love you.
Find them.
Paul?
Paul.
I'm here. I'm here. Hey.
What happened?
He's dead.
His vital signs are so
low, they can't be detected.
But he's alive.
What did you do to him?
No, not that. Why
would he do that?
Why would you do that?
Chani, his body is fighting the
poison and he needs your help.
You do it.
You did this to him.
You did this to your own son!
You do it!
Fix it yourself.
Chani, you might not believe in
the prophecy, but you're a part of it.
You're the poison.
You and your lies.
Why would you do this?
Do it.
Desert Spring tears.
Kwisatz Haderach,
climb up. Arise.
Usul, I'm here. I'm here.
Are you okay?
Yes.
Are you sure?
Thanks to you.
I'm sorry about Chani.
She'll come to understand.
I've seen it.
You can see?
The visions are clear now.
I see possible
futures. All at once.
Our enemies are all around us.
And in so many
futures, they prevail.
But I do see a way.
There is a narrow way through.
I saw our bloodline, Mother.
Written across time.
You are the daughter of
Baron Vladimir Harkonnen.
Did my father know?
I didn't know myself, until
I took the worm's poison.
We're Harkonnens.
So this is how we'll survive.
By being Harkonnens.
We must talk.
Stilgar, you can stop
this. Do you hear me?
You have the power to stop this.
Northern woman!
You are not allowed to
speak inside the circle.
If you want to speak,
you know what to do.
Stilgar, please.
For Arrakis' sake.
This prophecy is
how they enslave us!
How they dominate...
You'll get yourself in trouble.
This is none of your business.
Rabban Harkonnen
himself killed my family.
He gave me this scar
to remember him by.
This is all of my business.
Only tribe leaders can speak.
If you wish to share your voice,
you must take his
place by defeating him
and returning his
water to the well.
You think I'm stupid enough to
deprive myself of the best of us?
Take my life, Usul.
It is the only way.
I'm pointing the way!
Slow down.
But you think you
could have a chance.
Dune.
Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan
al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan al-Gaib!
Muad'Dib!
Muad'Dib.
This is my father's
ducal signet.
I am Paul
Muad'Dib Atreides,
Duke of Arrakis.
Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan
al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan al-Gaib!
Paul
Atreides is still alive.
He challenges my father.
You've never been on Arrakis.
It's quite impressive.
You'll see.
Was this all upon your advice?
What?
Did you counsel my father
to exterminate the Atreides?
Of course I did. Why else
would it have happened?
You tried to sacrifice
an entire bloodline.
And I was right to do it.
The Kwisatz Haderach
is a form of power
that our world has not yet seen.
The ultimate power.
For ninety generations,
we have supervised
House Atreides.
They were promising, but they
were becoming dangerously defiant.
Their bloodline had
to be terminated.
That is why we have put
many bloodlines at work.
Several prospects.
But it's backfired.
Paul is alive.
And if he defeats
Feyd-Rautha, my father...
Your father will lose the
throne no matter who prevails.
But there is one way your
family can remain in power
and, through you, the
continuation of our stewardship.
One. Way.
Are you prepared?
You've been preparing me
my whole life, Reverend Mother.
You're heading
north with the others?
I'm Fedaykin.
I follow my leaders. If
fighting goes north, I go north.
Paul didn't have
a choice, Chani.
I won't be fighting for him.
I'm fighting for my people.
I came to wish you best of luck.
I'd wish you the same,
but it seems you've
won your battle.
He took the bait.
The
Emperor's very obliging.
He's right on time.
What is he doing here?
I brought spice
production under control.
What do we do?
Send messages to
the Great Houses.
Tell them that Arrakis is
under Sardaukar attack.
Tell them, their future
hangs in the balance.
When the
storm hits this ridge,
Gurney will open the
way for you, Stilgar,
so you can enter the
basin from the West
and distract their
defense systems.
Chani, I want you
and your Fedaykin
to then attack from the East,
inside the basin.
I'll strike from the
North, head on,
with the Fundamentalist troops.
And I'll serve
Arrakeen for dessert.
Remember, I need
the Emperor alive.
Baron,
do you have any idea who
this Muad'Dib could be?
Some fanatic, your
Majesty. That's all we know.
More. More. Give me more.
He's a madman!
- Mad?
- All Fremen are mad.
That's all you know?
Really?
Muad'Dib is dead.
Or he went hiding in
the Southern storms
which means the same thing.
Your Majesty,
the sand storm
that's approaching
threatens the
integrity of our shields.
We recommend
going back into orbit.
Well, the mountains will
protect us from most of it,
your Majesty.
Baron, have you
ever investigated
the south regions of Arrakis?
Well, the entire
region is uninhabitable.
It's well known, your Majesty.
Your uninhabited South
exhibits evidence
of human activity.
I wasn't aware of this.
I swear to you, I wasn't
aware of any of this.
Muad'Dib is alive.
I must find him.
Fire!
Sardaukar! On guard!
Sardaukar!
Grandfather.
You die like an animal.
Muad'Dib.
Rabban!
Look who's back from the dead.
For my Duke, and my friends.
Warships.
The Great Houses.
Gurney, it's time.
Bring the prisoners.
My Lord.
This isn't over yet.
I want you to know...
I will love you as
long as I breathe.
There is a massed
armada in orbit.
You're facing a full
invasion, Fremen.
How can you be so sure
the Great Houses are here for me?
They may be curious to hear my
side of the story, don't you think?
I am Paul Atreides, son of
Leto Atreides, Duke of Arrakis.
- Gurney.
- My Lord.
Send a warning to all ships.
If the Great Houses attack, our
atomics will obliterate all spice fields.
- You're out of your mind.
- He's bluffing.
Consider what you're
about to do, Paul Atreides.
Silence!
Abomination.
Message sent, my Lord.
As a servant of the Imperium,
you will bow at my feet.
Your feet? You'll be
lucky to keep your head.
I'll take the hand
of your daughter.
She will remain safe.
And we will rule
together over the Empire.
But you...
You have to
answer for my father.
Do you know why I killed him?
Because he was a man
who believed in the
rules of the heart.
But the heart is
not meant to rule.
In other words...
your father was a weak man.
Stand or choose your champion.
I
am here, Atreides.
I need a blade.
Accept mine.
Do not stain your
hands on this animal.
Let me deal with him.
It's my burden, Gurney.
Why does he take such risks?
Muad'Dib leads the way.
I'm happy to finally
meet you, cousin.
Cousin? Is that right?
Well, you wouldn't be
the first relative I've killed.
May thy knife chip and shatter.
May
thy knife chip and shatter.
She's your pet?
Any special
attention for the pet?
You have fought well, Atreides.
Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan
al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
You
should've believed.
You chose the wrong side.
Side?
You, of all people, should know.
There are no sides...
Reverend Mother.
The life debt has been paid.
Spare my father now and
I will be your willing bride.
The throne will be yours.
My Lord,
the Great Houses have answered.
They refuse
to honor your ascendancy.
We await your orders,
Lisan al-Gaib.
Lead them to Paradise.
Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
What is happening, Mother?
Your brother attacks
the Great Houses.
The Holy War begins.